ebookaddicts.net 2019-06-19

# Privacy Policy – eBook Addicts

This privacy policy notice is for this website; www.ebookaddcits.net and served by Fee Kelly from eBook Addicts and governs the privacy of those who use it. You can contact me at ebookaddictsuk@gmail.com if you require any further information. The purpose of this policy is to explain to you how we receive, collect use and protect your personal information while browsing or using this website, including your rights under current laws and regulations. If you do not agree to the following policy you may wish to cease viewing / using this website.

**Policy key definitions:**  
“I”, “our”, “us”, or “we” refer to the business, [eBook Addicts].  
“you”, “the user” refer to the person(s) using this website.  
GDPR means General Data Protection Act.  
PECR means Privacy & Electronic Communications Regulation.  
ICO means Information Commissioner’s Office.  
Cookies mean small files stored on a users computer or device.

**_Data our website collects and how it is used_**  
**  
****Information you voluntarily submit to the website:**  
We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the website by leaving a public comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form. I will never sell or give away this information, nor will I ever sell or give away your e-mail address should you contact me.

**Comments:**  
When leaving a comment on this blog, you will be required to enter some basic personal information, such as your name, email address and blog URL. This data is only used to keep you updated with any comment threads you have expressed interest in. This data is not used to contact you outwith the blog, and is not passed on to any third parties. This data is hosted within our WordPress blog.

**Automatically-Collected Information:**  
We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the website. For example, when you use the website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the website, such as links clicked. We can not use the information gathered to identify and connect to you as a person.

**Cookies:**  
We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the website.

**Third-party use of personal information:**  
We will not share your information with third parties unless you explicitly authorize us to do so. Additionally, the website uses third-party service providers to service various aspects of the website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies. The website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

Google Analytics  
To track website usage and provide information such as referring websites and user actions on the website, visitor numbers and data such as countries being visited by. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.

Social Media networks  
For automatically viewing our website information across social media networks that you have given consent to, along with any other information you have given them, for example: Facebook, Twitter, Google+.

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications.

This list may be amended from time to time in the website’s sole discretion. Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent.

**Anonymous data:**  
From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

**How your data is used:**

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

  * To operate and maintain the Website;
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries;
  * To provide you with user support;
  * To track and measure advertising and usage on the Website;
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

If, as determined by us, the lawful basis upon which we process your personal information changes, we will notify you about the change and any new lawful basis to be used if required. We shall stop processing your personal information if the lawful basis used is no longer relevant.

**_Your individual rights_**

Under the GDPR your rights are as follows. You can read more about your rights in details here;  

the right to be informed;  
the right of access;  
the right to rectification;  
the right to erasure;  
the right to restrict processing;  
the right to data portability;  
the right to object; and  
the right not to be subject to automated decision-making including profiling.  
You also have the right to complain to the ICO [[www.ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/)] if you feel there is a problem with the way we are handling your data.

Opt-out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at ebookaddcitsuk@gmail.com to be removed from our mailing list.

Access – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to ebookaddictsuk@gmail.com.

Amend – You may amend or update your personal information by following the update profile links in our emails or by contacting us at ebookaddictsuk@gmail.com.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to ebookaddictsuk@gmail.com.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law. We handle subject access requests in accordance with the GDPR.

**Internet cookies**  
We use cookies on this website to provide you with a better user experience. We do this by placing a small text file on your device / computer hard drive to track how you use the website, to record or log whether you have seen particular messages that we display, to keep you logged into the website where applicable, to display relevant adverts or content, referred you to a third party website, to be able to respond to your comments.

Some cookies are required to enjoy and use the full functionality of this website.

We use a cookie control system which allows you to accept the use of cookies, and control which cookies are saved to your device / computer. Some cookies will be saved for specific time periods, where others may last indefinitely. Your web browser should provide you with the controls to manage and delete cookies from your device, please see your web browser options.

**Transparent Privacy Explanations**  
We have provided some further explanations about user privacy and the way we use this website to help promote a transparent and honest user privacy methodology.

**Sponsored links, affiliate tracking & commissions**  
Our website may contain adverts, sponsored and affiliate links on some pages. These are typically served through advertising partners such as; Google Adsense, eBay Partner Network, Amazon Affiliates, or are self served through our own means. We only use trusted advertising partners who each have high standards of user privacy and security. However we do not control the actual adverts seen / displayed by our advertising partners.

Clickable sponsored or affiliate links may be displayed as a website URL like this; www.ebookaddcits.net or as a titled text link like this: eBook Addicts.

Clicking on any adverts, sponsored or affiliate links may track your actions by using a cookie saved to your device. You can read more about cookies on this website above. Your actions are usually recorded as a referral from our website by this cookie. In most cases we earn a very small commission from the advertiser or advertising partner, at no cost to you, whether you make a purchase on their website or not.

We use advertising partners in these ways to help generate an income from the website, which allows us to continue our work and provide you with the best overall experience and valued information.

If you have any concerns about this we suggest you do not click on any adverts, sponsored or affiliate links found throughout the website.

**Email marketing messages & subscription**

At this time eBook Addicts does not operate a EMS or subscription service.

**Security**  
The security of your Personal Information is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

#### Resources & further information

Privacy Notice Policy Base: v.4.0 May 2018
